<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nino wicaksono on Nino Wicaksono</title>
    <link>https://ninovsnino.io/tags/nino-wicaksono/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nino wicaksono on Nino Wicaksono</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 05:17:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ninovsnino.io/tags/nino-wicaksono/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>One Day Bureaucracy</title>
      <link>https://ninovsnino.io/posts/one-day-bureaucracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2012 05:17:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninovsnino.io/posts/one-day-bureaucracy/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks back I was going back to Jakarta, the capital. The last time I visit Jakarta was alone, for just 2 days on weekends, reach Jakarta on Friday night, and return back Sunday night. Now I am going with my family. We had planned this trip months before. Me, Wulan, and Nina finally has a chance to travel together. We never had a chance to travel together so far, the arrangement usually goes like this, Wulan and Nina, they will go first, and later I pick them up then we had chance travel together back to Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIM Internasional</title>
      <link>https://ninovsnino.io/posts/sim-internasional/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 15:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ninovsnino.io/posts/sim-internasional/</guid>
      <description>Selama ini saya menikmati transportasi umum di luar negri, bagi saya transportasi umum yang layak dan nyaman adalah syarat negara maju, artinya negara yang sudah bertindak memikirkan rakyatnya. Saya bersyukur di Singapura karena disini hampir semua tempat tujuan yang ingin saya kunjungi memiliki akses transportasi umum. Di beberapa tempat memang sulit dijangkau dengan jalur bis, ada tempat-tempat makan yang sedikit mahal mewah dan unik seperti dempsey road atau kemarin saya menemukan tempat baru di belakang fusionpolis, atau bagi orang Indonesia, agak sulit juga menuju KBRI Singapura kan?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
